<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <channel>
    <xhtml:meta xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="robots" content="noindex" />
    <title>Ron's bookshelf: reference</title>
    <copyright><![CDATA[Copyright (C) 2022 Goodreads Inc. All rights reserved.]]>
    </copyright>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/list_rss/2401015?key=S32et3Fz0RHR5EvFXCAxe6F3vqx_GasSQVSDLnEQMQ_uO2kT&shelf=reference]]></link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/list_rss/2401015?key=S32et3Fz0RHR5EvFXCAxe6F3vqx_GasSQVSDLnEQMQ_uO2kT&amp;shelf=reference" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description><![CDATA[Ron's bookshelf: reference]]></description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 08:39:40 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <image>
      <title>Ron's bookshelf: reference</title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/list_rss/2401015?key=S32et3Fz0RHR5EvFXCAxe6F3vqx_GasSQVSDLnEQMQ_uO2kT&shelf=reference]]></link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>41</height>
      <url>https://www.goodreads.com/images/layout/goodreads_logo_144.jpg</url>
    </image>
    
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1336673411?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 16 Jul 2015 08:39:40 -0700]]></pubDate>
    <title><![CDATA[Power Shift: From Fossil Energy to Dynamic Solar Power]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1336673411?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>25463452</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1430508761l/25463452._SX50_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1430508761l/25463452._SX50_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1430508761l/25463452._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1430508761l/25463452.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[You are part of the grand transition that is underway in energy, but you are probably wondering what it all means for you. Human society has committed to getting off fossil fuels because they are warming our planet, and this shift will engage everyone. Why? Because everyone uses energy. Today you have choices in energy that you never had before, and your choices will affect many generations to come. This book will bring you up to speed on your many options in energy, all explained in terms that anyone can understand.<br /><br />Power Shift: From Fossil Energy to Dynamic Solar Power retells human history through the lens of energy, explains the science behind the crisis–in clear, succinct language that anyone can understand—and provides a detailed blueprint for the future, from governmental, commercial, and individual perspectives.<br /><br />Today, we’ve become mired in partisan bickering among politicians and oil, gas, and coal lobbying interests who insist that fossil fuels are necessary for jobs and the US economy. However, this narrow debate has failed to notice that the world has already embarked on a transformation in how we use energy that is so fundamental, it defines a new Solar Epoch, as monumental as the discovery of fire, the development of agriculture, and the exploitation of fossil fuels in previous centuries.<br /><br />The truth is that solar power–getting radically cheaper by the year–is not only a viable solution but, as the author states, “forms a clean energy system that can completely replace fossil fuels. We can gradually phase them in so that in 50 years we’ll be 100% solar-powered. And because solar energy does not run out like fossil fuels, we will never need to go looking for another energy source again.”<br />Unlike other books on global warming and solar energy, Power Shift presents visionary plans for governments, corporations, and individuals concerned about climate change.<br /><br />And the author has “put his money where his mouth is.” Having built a solar home in Santa Cruz County in 1997 and outfitted it with an off-grid solar photovoltaic (PV) system, Stayton cites numerous personal examples to inspire others to take similar action.<br /><br />Destined to become a classic in the field, and soon to be adopted as a basic text in college and university environmental studies programs, Power Shift is an indispensable reference for researchers and global leaders, a valuable staff training tool for solar companies, and a compelling, inspirational read for anyone eager to learn the truth about global warming and to participate “from the ground up” in the new Solar Epoch.<br /><br />Reader-friendly with beautiful illustrations and firmly grounded in current science, Power Shift also forges a cautionary tale of what lies ahead if we don’t start acting now: “We seem to be waiting for a sign,” Stayton writes, “a sudden event so catastrophic that it compels us to overcome political differences and take action. However, this disaster does not rush upon us like a hurricane, but instead slowly erodes our foundation, like termites. If we wait until the house collapses, we will have waited too long.”<br /><br />If you buy only one book on the topic of climate change or solar power–for yourself, family, friends, or colleagues–you can depend on Power Shift to serve as a comprehensive, eye-opening, educational resource for years to come.]]></book_description>
    <book id="25463452">
      <num_pages>346</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>Robert Arthur Stayton</author_name>
    <isbn>099047920X</isbn>
    <user_name>Ron</user_name>
    <user_rating>5</user_rating>
    <user_read_at><![CDATA[Thu, 16 Jul 2015 08:39:40 -0700]]></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Thu, 16 Jul 2015 08:39:40 -0700]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Thu, 16 Jul 2015 08:27:20 -0700]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves><![CDATA[nonfiction, reference, science]]></user_shelves>
    <user_review><![CDATA["Power Shift" really should be required reading for all. This book clearly and concisely explains the evolution of mankind's use of energy and the role of energy in our rise as dominant species of planet Earth.<br /><br />Anyone involved in the climate debate or the impact of fossil fuel use on the climate should read this book. Our educators should read this book. In fact, I would recommend everybody read this book.<br /><br />Don't think that because Stayton provides a clear and concise explanation of the science and evolution of energy use by humans that this book will not inform the scientific community. I have a Ph.D. in Mathematics, a rich history of study in the physical sciences, and a lifelong career as a computer scientist yet every page of this book managed to inform me in ways I had not previously connected.<br /><br />Read it.]]></user_review>
    <average_rating>4.56</average_rating>
    <book_published>2015</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25463452-power-shift?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="Power Shift: From Fossil Energy to Dynamic Solar Power" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1430508761l/25463452._SX50_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: Robert Arthur Stayton<br/>
                                      name: Ron<br/>
                                      average rating: 4.56<br/>
                                      book published: 2015<br/>
                                      rating: 5<br/>
                                      read at: 2015/07/16<br/>
                                      date added: 2015/07/16<br/>
                                      shelves: nonfiction, reference, science<br/>
                                      review: <br/>"Power Shift" really should be required reading for all. This book clearly and concisely explains the evolution of mankind's use of energy and the role of energy in our rise as dominant species of planet Earth.<br /><br />Anyone involved in the climate debate or the impact of fossil fuel use on the climate should read this book. Our educators should read this book. In fact, I would recommend everybody read this book.<br /><br />Don't think that because Stayton provides a clear and concise explanation of the science and evolution of energy use by humans that this book will not inform the scientific community. I have a Ph.D. in Mathematics, a rich history of study in the physical sciences, and a lifelong career as a computer scientist yet every page of this book managed to inform me in ways I had not previously connected.<br /><br />Read it.<br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/151869773?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Mar 2011 13:59:52 -0800]]></pubDate>
    <title><![CDATA[Empire of the Summer Moon: Quanah Parker and the Rise and Fall of the Comanches, the Most Powerful Indian Tribe in American History]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/151869773?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>7648269</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1395176404l/7648269._SY75_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1395176404l/7648269._SY75_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1395176404l/7648269._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1395176404l/7648269.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[<p>In the tradition of <i>Bury My Heart at Wounded Knee, </i>a stunningly vivid historical account of the forty-year battle between Comanche Indians and white settlers for control of the American West, centering on Quanah, the greatest Comanche chief of them all.</p><p>S. C. Gwynne’s <i>Empire of the Summer Moon</i><b> </b>spans two astonishing stories. The first traces the rise and fall of the Comanches, the most powerful Indian tribe in American history. The second entails one of the most remarkable narratives ever to come out of the Old West: the epic saga of the pioneer woman Cynthia Ann Parker and her mixed-blood son Quanah, who became the last and greatest chief of the Comanches. </p><p>Although readers may be more familiar with the tribal names Apache and Sioux, it was in fact the legendary fighting ability of the Comanches that determined just how and when the American West opened up. Comanche boys became adept bareback riders by age six; full Comanche braves were considered the best horsemen who ever rode. They were so masterful at war and so skillful with their arrows and lances that they stopped the northern drive of colonial Spain from Mexico and halted the French expansion westward from Louisiana. White settlers arriving in Texas from the eastern United States were surprised to find the frontier being rolled <i>backward </i>by Comanches incensed by the invasion of their tribal lands. So effective were the Comanches that they forced the creation of the Texas Rangers and account for the advent of the new weapon specifically designed to fight them: the six-gun. </p><p>The war with the Comanches lasted four decades, in effect holding up the development of the new American nation. Gwynne’s exhilarating account delivers a sweeping narrative that encompasses Spanish colonialism, the Civil War, the destruction of the buffalo herds, and the arrival of the railroads—a historical feast for anyone interested in how the United States came into being. </p><p>Against this backdrop Gwynne presents the compelling drama of Cynthia Ann Parker, a lovely nine-year-old girl with cornflower-blue eyes who was kidnapped by Comanches from the far Texas frontier in 1836. She grew to love her captors and became infamous as the "White Squaw" who refused to return until her tragic capture by Texas Rangers in 1860. More famous still was her son Quanah, a warrior who was never defeated and whose guerrilla wars in the Texas Panhandle made him a legend. </p><p></p><p>S. C. Gwynne’s account of these events is meticulously researched, intellectually provocative, and, above all, thrillingly told.</p>]]></book_description>
    <book id="7648269">
      <num_pages>371</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>S.C. Gwynne</author_name>
    <isbn>1416591052</isbn>
    <user_name>Ron</user_name>
    <user_rating>5</user_rating>
    <user_read_at><![CDATA[Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 -0700]]></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Mar 2011 13:59:52 -0800]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Thu, 03 Mar 2011 13:46:44 -0800]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves><![CDATA[reference, nonfiction, biography]]></user_shelves>
    <user_review><![CDATA[This extensively researched history of the Comanche should be required reading for every American. Gwynne manages to transform what could be an exhaustively detailed dry account into a gripping tale of historical scale. Not for the squeamish, Gwynne pulls no punches in his account - a major plus as far as I am concerned as the truth in this chapter should not be edited. The book contains tons of fascinating fact. For instance, did you know that Buffalo Hump (born ca. late 1790s to early 19th century — died 1870) was a Native American War Chief of the Penateka band of the Comanche Indians. His Nʉmʉ tekwapu (Comanche) name, properly transliterated, was Po-cha-na-quar-hip which meant "erection that won't go down" ? Or, that Isa-tai ("Wolf's Vulva" c.1840 — c.1890) was a Comanche warrior and medicine man of the Quahadi band. Originally named Quenatosavit (White Eagle), after the debacle at Adobe Walls he was known as Isa-tai which translates as "wolf's vulva" or "coyote vagina" ?<br /><br />Gwynne uses the life of Quanah Parker and Quanah's family as his focus to tie the epic saga together and provide a bigger than life character the reader can bond with. The Parker family could have their own book and the story of Quanah Parker is uniquely apropos as a microcosm of the larger story of the Native American tribes. If I could recommend only one book and it couldn't be any Brautigan or Vonnegut or Dick or Steinbeck or Robbins or McMurtry plus it had to be non-fiction then this would be it! :)]]></user_review>
    <average_rating>4.19</average_rating>
    <book_published>2010</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7648269-empire-of-the-summer-moon?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="Empire of the Summer Moon: Quanah Parker and the Rise and Fall of the Comanches, the Most Powerful Indian Tribe in American History" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1395176404l/7648269._SY75_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: S.C. Gwynne<br/>
                                      name: Ron<br/>
                                      average rating: 4.19<br/>
                                      book published: 2010<br/>
                                      rating: 5<br/>
                                      read at: 2010/11/01<br/>
                                      date added: 2011/03/03<br/>
                                      shelves: reference, nonfiction, biography<br/>
                                      review: <br/>This extensively researched history of the Comanche should be required reading for every American. Gwynne manages to transform what could be an exhaustively detailed dry account into a gripping tale of historical scale. Not for the squeamish, Gwynne pulls no punches in his account - a major plus as far as I am concerned as the truth in this chapter should not be edited. The book contains tons of fascinating fact. For instance, did you know that Buffalo Hump (born ca. late 1790s to early 19th century — died 1870) was a Native American War Chief of the Penateka band of the Comanche Indians. His Nʉmʉ tekwapu (Comanche) name, properly transliterated, was Po-cha-na-quar-hip which meant "erection that won't go down" ? Or, that Isa-tai ("Wolf's Vulva" c.1840 — c.1890) was a Comanche warrior and medicine man of the Quahadi band. Originally named Quenatosavit (White Eagle), after the debacle at Adobe Walls he was known as Isa-tai which translates as "wolf's vulva" or "coyote vagina" ?<br /><br />Gwynne uses the life of Quanah Parker and Quanah's family as his focus to tie the epic saga together and provide a bigger than life character the reader can bond with. The Parker family could have their own book and the story of Quanah Parker is uniquely apropos as a microcosm of the larger story of the Native American tribes. If I could recommend only one book and it couldn't be any Brautigan or Vonnegut or Dick or Steinbeck or Robbins or McMurtry plus it had to be non-fiction then this would be it! :)<br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/60346104?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jun 2009 16:24:31 -0700]]></pubDate>
    <title>First Lessons in Philology</title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/60346104?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>6558201</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1245453859l/6558201._SX50_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1245453859l/6558201._SX50_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1245453859l/6558201._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1245453859l/6558201.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[A beautifully bound and wonderfully written introduction to the history of language.]]></book_description>
    <book id="6558201">
      <num_pages>142</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>Bernard Bigsby</author_name>
    <isbn></isbn>
    <user_name>Ron</user_name>
    <user_rating>5</user_rating>
    <user_read_at></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jun 2009 16:24:31 -0700]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jun 2009 16:24:31 -0700]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves><![CDATA[essays, philosophy, reference, science]]></user_shelves>
    <user_review></user_review>
    <average_rating>5.00</average_rating>
    <book_published>1879</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6558201-first-lessons-in-philology?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="First Lessons in Philology" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1245453859l/6558201._SX50_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: Bernard Bigsby<br/>
                                      name: Ron<br/>
                                      average rating: 5.00<br/>
                                      book published: 1879<br/>
                                      rating: 5<br/>
                                      read at: <br/>
                                      date added: 2009/06/19<br/>
                                      shelves: essays, philosophy, reference, science<br/>
                                      review: <br/><br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/60344178?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jun 2009 16:01:42 -0700]]></pubDate>
    <title>Integral Yoga Hatha</title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/60344178?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>649512</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1352793612l/649512._SX50_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1352793612l/649512._SX50_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1352793612l/649512._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1352793612l/649512.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[In print constantly since 1970, this large format Hatha Yoga instruction guide is now recognized as a classic in its field. Over 160 large photographs show Hatha expert Sri Swami Satchidananda performing more than 80 postures, breathing practices, relaxation, cleansing and concentration techniques. Instructions are easy to follow and describe how the body and mind benefit from each pose. Practice routines for beginning, intermediate and advanced students are suggested.]]></book_description>
    <book id="649512">
      <num_pages>189</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>Satchidananda</author_name>
    <isbn>093204042X</isbn>
    <user_name>Ron</user_name>
    <user_rating>5</user_rating>
    <user_read_at></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jun 2009 16:01:42 -0700]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jun 2009 16:01:42 -0700]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves>philosophy, reference</user_shelves>
    <user_review></user_review>
    <average_rating>4.32</average_rating>
    <book_published>1970</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/649512.Integral_Yoga_Hatha?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="Integral Yoga Hatha" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1352793612l/649512._SX50_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: Satchidananda<br/>
                                      name: Ron<br/>
                                      average rating: 4.32<br/>
                                      book published: 1970<br/>
                                      rating: 5<br/>
                                      read at: <br/>
                                      date added: 2009/06/19<br/>
                                      shelves: philosophy, reference<br/>
                                      review: <br/><br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/60343902?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jun 2009 15:58:58 -0700]]></pubDate>
    <title>The Science of Hitting</title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/60343902?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>205658</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1386924399l/205658._SX50_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1386924399l/205658._SX50_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1386924399l/205658._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1386924399l/205658.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[<b>“Baseball’s last .400 hitter share[s] his secrets in this primer still used at all levels of the game.” —Paul Dickson, author of <i>Bill Veeck: </i><i>Baseball’s</i><i> Greatest Maverick</i></b><br /> <br />Now fully revised with new illustrations and diagrams, the classic—and still the greatest—book on hitting from the last baseball player to break the magic .400 barrier, Ted Williams.<br /><br />Ted Williams was arguably the greatest pure hitter who ever lived. A lifelong student of hitting, he sought advice from every great hitter—and pitcher—he met. Drawing on that advice, as well as his own legendary life in baseball, Williams produced the all-time batting classic, <i>The Science of Hitting</i>. Using its detailed illustrations, anecdotes, and concise coaching, players of all skill levels will learn how to improve their fundamentals and gain keen insights into the finer points of hitting, including:<br /> <br />-How to Think Like a Pitcher and Guess the Pitch<br /> -The Three Cardinal Rules for Developing a Smooth Line-Driving Swing<br /> -The Secrets of Hip and Wrist Action<br /> -Pitch Selection<br /> -Bunting<br /> -Hitting the Opposite Way<br /> <br /><i>The Science of Hitting</i> is a must-read for all baseball players looking to improve their turn at bat and for all coaches and parents teaching the sport.]]></book_description>
    <book id="205658">
      <num_pages>96</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>Ted Williams</author_name>
    <isbn></isbn>
    <user_name>Ron</user_name>
    <user_rating>5</user_rating>
    <user_read_at></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jun 2009 15:58:58 -0700]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Fri, 19 Jun 2009 15:58:58 -0700]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves>essays, reference</user_shelves>
    <user_review></user_review>
    <average_rating>4.28</average_rating>
    <book_published>1971</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/205658.The_Science_of_Hitting?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="The Science of Hitting" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1386924399l/205658._SX50_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: Ted Williams<br/>
                                      name: Ron<br/>
                                      average rating: 4.28<br/>
                                      book published: 1971<br/>
                                      rating: 5<br/>
                                      read at: <br/>
                                      date added: 2009/06/19<br/>
                                      shelves: essays, reference<br/>
                                      review: <br/><br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/59527800?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jun 2009 11:59:45 -0700]]></pubDate>
    <title><![CDATA[Slayer Slang: A Buffy the Vampire Slayer Lexicon]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/59527800?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>140456</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1340737779l/140456._SY75_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1340737779l/140456._SY75_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1340737779l/140456._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1340737779l/140456.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[In its seven years on television, <em>Buffy the Vampire Slayer</em> earned critical acclaim and a massive cult following among teen viewers. One of the most distinguishing features of the show is the innovative way its writers play with language--fabricating new words, morphing existing ones, and<br />throwing usage on its head. The result has been a strikingly resonant lexicon that reflects the power of both youth culture and television in the evolution of American slang. Using the show to illustrate how new slang is formed, transformed, and transmitted, <em>Slayer Slang</em> is one of those rare books<br />that combines a serious explanation of a pop culture phenomenon with an engrossing read for Buffy fans, language mavens, and pop culture critics. Noted linguist Michael Adams offers a synopsis of the program's history, an essay on the nature and evolution of the show's language, and a detailed<br />glossary of slayer slang, annotated with actual dialogue. Introduced by Jane Espenson, one of the show's most inventive writers (and herself a linguist), <em>Slayer Slang</em> offers a quintessential example of contemporary youth culture serving as a vehicle for slang.<br />]]></book_description>
    <book id="140456">
      <num_pages>320</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>Michael         Adams</author_name>
    <isbn>0195175999</isbn>
    <user_name>Ron</user_name>
    <user_rating>5</user_rating>
    <user_read_at></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jun 2009 11:59:45 -0700]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jun 2009 11:59:45 -0700]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves>reference</user_shelves>
    <user_review></user_review>
    <average_rating>4.01</average_rating>
    <book_published>2003</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/140456.Slayer_Slang?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="Slayer Slang: A Buffy the Vampire Slayer Lexicon" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1340737779l/140456._SY75_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: Michael         Adams<br/>
                                      name: Ron<br/>
                                      average rating: 4.01<br/>
                                      book published: 2003<br/>
                                      rating: 5<br/>
                                      read at: <br/>
                                      date added: 2009/06/13<br/>
                                      shelves: reference<br/>
                                      review: <br/><br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/59527766?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jun 2009 11:59:13 -0700]]></pubDate>
    <title><![CDATA[The Sunnydale High Yearbook (Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 3, #24)]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/59527766?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>293364</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1388221981l/293364._SX50_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1388221981l/293364._SX50_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1388221981l/293364._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1388221981l/293364.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[It's senior year for Buffy Summers and her friends. And that means homecoming, senior prom, finals, graduation—all the usual evil doings guaranteed to make the Chosen One long for recess. <br /><br />Slayer duties caused Buffy to miss picking up her Yearbook, so Willow took it for her and enlisted the help of Xander, Oz, Cordelia, Giles, and Angel to make it truly special. Filled with personal notes, candid photos, and in-jokes about Slayerfest, Halloween, substitute teachers, the principal who was eaten, Ascension, etc.—Buffy's Yearbook is part school publication, part memory book. <br /><br />Written by the authors of the bestselling <i>The Watcher's Guide</i>, this keepsake volume is packed with key references to the show and characters, 32 full-color pages of fan-favorite moments, and Graduation photos.]]></book_description>
    <book id="293364">
      <num_pages>112</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>Christopher Golden</author_name>
    <isbn>067103541X</isbn>
    <user_name>Ron</user_name>
    <user_rating>5</user_rating>
    <user_read_at></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jun 2009 11:59:13 -0700]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jun 2009 11:59:13 -0700]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves>reference</user_shelves>
    <user_review></user_review>
    <average_rating>4.08</average_rating>
    <book_published>1999</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/293364.The_Sunnydale_High_Yearbook?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="The Sunnydale High Yearbook (Buffy the Vampire Slayer: Season 3, #24)" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1388221981l/293364._SX50_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: Christopher Golden<br/>
                                      name: Ron<br/>
                                      average rating: 4.08<br/>
                                      book published: 1999<br/>
                                      rating: 5<br/>
                                      read at: <br/>
                                      date added: 2009/06/13<br/>
                                      shelves: reference<br/>
                                      review: <br/><br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/59527664?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jun 2009 11:57:52 -0700]]></pubDate>
    <title><![CDATA[Buffy the Vampire Slayer: The Watcher's Guide, Volume 1]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/59527664?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>293389</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1315830118l/293389._SX50_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1315830118l/293389._SX50_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1315830118l/293389._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1315830118l/293389.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[As long as there have been vampires, there has been the Slayer. One girl in all the world, to find them where they gather and to stop the spread of their evil and the swell of their members. She is the Slayer.]]></book_description>
    <book id="293389">
      <num_pages>298</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>Christopher Golden</author_name>
    <isbn>0671024337</isbn>
    <user_name>Ron</user_name>
    <user_rating>4</user_rating>
    <user_read_at></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jun 2009 11:57:52 -0700]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Sat, 13 Jun 2009 11:57:52 -0700]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves>reference</user_shelves>
    <user_review></user_review>
    <average_rating>4.15</average_rating>
    <book_published>1998</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/293389.Buffy_the_Vampire_Slayer?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="Buffy the Vampire Slayer: The Watcher&#39;s Guide, Volume 1" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1315830118l/293389._SX50_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: Christopher Golden<br/>
                                      name: Ron<br/>
                                      average rating: 4.15<br/>
                                      book published: 1998<br/>
                                      rating: 4<br/>
                                      read at: <br/>
                                      date added: 2009/06/13<br/>
                                      shelves: reference<br/>
                                      review: <br/><br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
